## Violeta Sol Arias Hours

Salta - Salta, Argentina

(+54) 9 3875377584

### Frontend Developer

violehours@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/violetasolariashours

GitHub: https://github.com/VioleHours

Porfolio: https://violetahours.vercel.app/

TECH SKILLS: Javascript, Typescript, Python, PHP

FRONT-END: HTML5, Css3, ReactJs, ReduxJs, NextJs, TailwindCss, Angular, Bootstrap, Sass, Zustand

BACK-END: NodeJs, Express, Sequelize

BASE DE DATOS: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase

CMS: WordPress, WooCommerce, Elementor,

HERRAMIENTAS: Git/GitHub, VSCode, VisualStudio, Slack, Trello, Jira, Figma AGILE: Scrum

#### **WHOIAM**

I am a Frontend Developer and UX/UI Designer with a background in Audiovisual Production and Fashion Design. I specialize in creating attractive and functional user interfaces using modern technologies. My focus is on utilizing HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and various frameworks like React, Redux, and Next.js to develop intuitive and high-performance web experiences. With skills in agile methodologies and GIT, I have worked on both individual and group projects, which has helped me develop soft skills such as communication, teamwork, adaptability, and problem-solving.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE.

# Frontend Developer DASCalendar · Part-time

Oct 2023 - Mar 2024

- Design and development of a responsive and visually attractive website, ensuring an intuitive and pleasant user experience.
- Leadership as Scrum Master/Product Owner, facilitating meetings and ensuring effective implementation of agile methodologies.
- Team collaboration with a focus on frontend development using React, TypeScript, and Tailwind CSS.

## Odoo Developer InkuA · Internship

May 2023 - Oct 2023

- Development of websites for NGOs and Odoo updates research for websites.
- Continuous research and updates to enhance website usability and functionality.
- Implementation of custom solutions in Odoo to optimize internal processes and improve efficiency.
- Active participation in meetings and brainstorming sessions to generate new strategies and innovative approaches.

### Full Stack Teaching Assistant Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

- Coordinating a group of students to achieve integration into the study team.
- Assisting in exercise resolution and promoting group collaboration (Pair Programming).
- Proposing ideas for improving Bootcamp processes.

# Camera Assistant Catholic University of Salta

Nov 2018 - Mar 2020

- Responsible for the proper maintenance of the camera during filming.
- Operation of television studio cameras for the courses of Broadcasting and Production and Direction

for Radio and Television.

#### PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

- UX/UI Design. Codo a Codo. 198 hours of theoretical-practical training. Aug 2023 Dec 2023.
- Full Stack Web Developer. Henry Bootcamp. 800 hours of theoretical-practical training. Oct 2022- Jul. 2023.
- Bachelor's Degree in Image and Sound. Catholic University of Salta. 19/50 approved subjects. 2018-2020

### **ADDITIONAL EDUCATION**

- Fashion Design/Personal Image Consulting. Roberto Piazza Salta High Fashion and Comprehensive Beauty Institute. 2021-2022
- Production and Direction for Radio and Television. Catholic University of Salta. 2019-2020

### **LANGUAGES**

- Spanish Native.
- English B2 Intermediate.

### **PROJECTS**

### Full Stack Web Developer - Countries PI

Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

Individual Project

In this project, I developed a SPA (Single Page Application) about countries and activities which can be created, assigned, and deleted. It also includes combined filters, pagination, and controlled forms, among other features.

Front: React, Redux, Css Back: NodeJs, Express

Database: PostgreSQL y Sequelize

### Full Stack Web Developer - PF e-latam

Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

Our project is an innovative e-commerce platform designed specifically for the dynamic and vibrant Latin American market. This platform serves as a virtual marketplace where administrators oversee business operations, while users interact with a wide range of products, reviews, and ratings. Users are free to explore an extensive catalog of products and make informed purchasing decisions.

Front: React, ReduxToolkit, Css, Vite

Back: NodeJs, Express.

Database: PostgreSQL y Sequelize.